<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cosmic Owl Studio</title>
    <description>Hello. Welcome to the weblog of Sean Sperte. This is a collection of notes related to design, technology, and faith.
</description>
    <link>http://chasemccoy.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://chasemccoy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 12:15:10 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 12:15:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Sea of Trolls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked this book because I had read it before and wanted to introduce Chase to it, but I found that the more I read the more I realized I had forgotten most of the story. It is a fantastic tale full of happiness, sadness, anger, and wonder. While it is the first of a trilogy, but works well as a stand-alone story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack and his younger sister Lucy are captured and enslaved by a group of fierce warriors called the berserkers. They are taken to a world full of new people and experiences. This book is full of references to Norse mythology and Anglo Saxon legends that only lend to the story telling in the book. The characters are full of life, and the more you live with the enemies in the book the more you come to like them despite their terrible traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/sea-of-trolls</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/sea-of-trolls</guid>
        
        
        <category>book-club</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ready Player One</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two books were mega popular this summer: &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/em&gt;. So after we finished up &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; we moved on to &lt;em&gt;RPO&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filled with tons of 1980’s pop-culture references, this book tells the story of a future when everyone on Earth escapes into a virtual reality game called the Oasis in order to avoid the slowly dying planet they live on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founder of the Oasis recently died, and when he did he promised his vast riches to whoever could find all of the easter eggs he had hid inside the game. The protagonist of the book gets wrapped up in the hunt for the easter egg, and it has consequences in both the virtual and real worlds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt;, this book was a lot of fun to read. It was one that kept you on the edge of your seat, and it also had a great sense of humor. You will especially love this book if you have a lot of knowledge about 80’s video games/movies/TV/etc. But even if you don’t, I really think you will still find this book entertaining. Because it’s set largely in a virtual reality, there are so many rules that the author is allowed to break. And that makes for a very fun, exciting novel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/rpo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/rpo</guid>
        
        
        <category>book-club</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Martian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After so much hype about this book and the upcoming movie, we decided to kick off the book club by reading &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already know, &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; is about the story of a NASA astronaut who gets stranded on Mars after his team is forced to evacuate early. Faced with certain doom and seemingly no hope of rescue, he is forced to rely on his wits to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was really great for a couple of reasons. The first was the unexpected sense of humor from the book’s protagonist. &lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; includes a lot of scientific explanations, and the humor really helped to keep it light and entertaining. Speaking of science, almost all of it in this book is accurate, which is really cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Martian&lt;/em&gt; was a really quick, funny, and exciting book to read. I highly recommend it if you haven’t read it already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/martian</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chasemccoy.github.io/book-club/martian</guid>
        
        
        <category>book-club</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cosmic Owl got its start when two best friends with a love for building cool things came together and decided to build cool things with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathan Ansel and Chase McCoy are two Computer Science students in Starkville, Mississippi with a penchant for good software. We are Apple fanboys, music aficionados, and design junkies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cosmic Owl is our creative outlet for a delightful combination of code and design. We look forward to making neat products and to working with interesting people. Please &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#064;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you want to work with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;— Nathan and Chase&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://chasemccoy.github.io/about</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://chasemccoy.github.io/about</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
